COLEMAN SANDERS III

3925 Monroe Street, Bellwood, IL 60104 (708) 970-6104 • colemansanders111@yahoo.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Skilled worker with construction and over twenty years maintenance experience in performing
routine, reparative and preventative maintenance in diverse industries. Adept at using hand tools,
power tools, heavy and industrial equipment to overhaul, repair, and install physical structures,
plumbing, assembly, soldering and carpentry. Also, familiar with hydraulic and pneumatic
systems. Successful in prioritizing work orders to restore and sustain facility operations while
simultaneously managing multiple repair projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Maintenance Technician I

Essendant Carol Stream, IL 10/2017-01/2018

- Performed preventive maintenance, trouble shooting, installation and repair
- Walked through inspection of conveyor systems to detect damage and malfunction of belt drives, chain drives, shafts, rollers and motors
- Monitored and inspected daily box erectors, shrink tunnel, pallet wrapper machines to ensure they
 were running properly and performed basic maintenance duties
- Rerouted electrical wiring and entered electrical panel to reset overloaded systems using Arch Blast training
- Obtained operator certification for Power Industrial Vehicles (PIV) Dock Stockers, Order Picker, Taylor Dunn, Walkie Ryder, Fork Lifts, Reach Truck and Sky Jack

Primary Maintenance

McDonalds Corp. Downers Grove, IL 04/2016-09/2017

- Installed, repaired and maintained restaurant grounds and equipment (replaced drive-thru intercoms, installed new refrigeration units, replaced old cash registers, etc.)
- Performed basic janitorial duties such as mopping, sweeping and dusting

Assembling Technician

Home Depot West Suburban Stores of IL 02/2016- 05/2017

- Prepared work to be accomplished by studying assembly instructions, blueprint specifications, and parts lists; gathering parts, subassemblies, tools, and materials
- Positioned parts and subassemblies by using templates or reading measurements.
- Resolved assembly problems by altering dimensions to meet specifications; notifying supervisor to obtain additional resources
- Kept equipment operational by completing preventive maintenance requirements; following manufacturer's instructions; troubleshooting malfunctions; calling for repairs

Service Technician

Sears Holding Group

Melrose Park, IL

05/2015-12/2015

- Set up shop, inventory all mechanical equipment needed to be service and repaired for residential and commercial use
- Specialized in removal and replacement of small block and big block two cycle engines which includes the external and internal parts
- Followed all safety, set-up procedures and blueprint specifications, completing all repairs
 notifying supervisor of my decision to allow or deny release of equipment within Sears guidelines
 and rules

Floor Care Technician

Loyola Medical Center

Maywood, IL

02/2014-05/2015

- Performed floor maintenance and operated and maintained all floor equipment
- Carried out all duties that were necessary in resolving reactionary activities, and reported the need for further maintenance and safety to supervising staff
- Carried out detailed evaluation of workshop equipment to ensure that they were in good condition for proper functioning

<u>Plumber</u>

Wal-Moor Inc.

Chicago, IL

08/2004-10/2010

- Installed exterior and interior piping for residences and industrial companies
- Repaired water and sewer lines along with installing pipes
- Rodded all waste lines, water ramming, cleaned and installed storm catch basins and grease traps
- Performed all duties at city and state code requirements

EDUCATION

ITT Technical Institute

Oak Brook, IL

03/2012-06/2012

Majored in Computer and Electronics Engineering Technology

College of Du Page

Glen Ellyn, IL

09/2012-04/2013

Majored in Electro Mechanical Maintenance

REFERENCES

Available upon request